Privacy Policy - iKeepSafe                         

Privacy Policy
--------------

The ikeepsafe.orgSM website, iKeepSafePrivacy.com and iKeepSafePrivacy.org are operated by the Internet Keep Safe CoalitionSM (IKSCSM) group.  The IKSCSM group comprises a partnership of governors, first spouses, government agencies, non-profit organizations, and corporate sponsors working to give parents, educators, and policymakers the information and tools which empower them to teach children the safe and healthy use of technology and the Internet.

It is our policy at the IKSCSM group to protect the privacy of those who visit our website. This policy explains what information we collect through the website and how we may use, disclose and share that information.  By using this site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  This policy may be updated as our organization changes.  When the policy changes, we will post a notice on our home page and at the top of this Privacy Policy page, and by any other means as required by law.  If you have any questions about this policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at [info@ikeepsafe.org](mailto:info@ikeepsafe.org).

**Collection of Personal Information**

In certain areas of our website we collect information from organizations and individuals who wish to participate in the Coalition.  For example, if you wish to receive a copy of a white paper, we may ask for your name, email address, school where employed (if applicable), and your role within the school.  We use this information to send you the information you’ve requested and to send you updates about topics that we believe might be of interest.  Schools requesting information about the Generation Safe materials are asked to provide a name, email address, school, school district, administrator type, stakeholder group, a user name and password.  The information is used to deliver the requested materials through the website, and to connect the user with others in their school who are also using Generation Safe materials.

We also collect information from individuals and organizations that reach us through the “Contact Us” section of the website, or that would like to schedule a media event with, or a presentation from, Faux Paw.

**Use of Personal Information**

We will use your Personal Information to provide you with additional materials and news about iKeepSafe and its programs that we believe may be of interest to you.  You may opt-out of receiving such information by contacting us at [info@ikeepsafe.org](mailto:info@ikeepsafe.org) or by selecting the “unsubscribe” link available in each email that we send.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

As a general policy, iKeepSafe does not sell, disclose or provide third-parties, including our third-party partners, with Personal Information about visitors to our website.  Personal Information, as used in this Privacy Policy, means last name, email address, street address, phone number, date-of-birth, and Social Security Number.  Personal Information excludes, however, Internet protocol address (“IP address”), cookies, device identifiers, geo-location, “URL’s” for web pages, and all other technical information.  Technical and other information is discussed below in the section entitled “Non-Personal Information.”

We delete user information periodically when it is no longer needed.

**User Choice**

If you would like to review or delete the Personal Information you have provided to us, please contact us atinfo@ikeepsafe.org.  Please note that we may request that you verify your identity prior to sharing information with you.

**Non-Personal Information:**

As is customary with most websites, our website collects and stores the name of the website and/or IP address you visited immediately prior to navigating to [ikeepsafe.org](http://ikeepsafe.org/); the IP address of the device and/or router you used to access the Internet; your browser software version; your type of operating system; the date and time our website was accessed; and other technical information about your device.. This information is only used for analytics, improving website performance, information security, to ensure proper website operation and for other internal purposes.

**Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Technologies**

Our websites, and the third parties that are “tagged” on our web pages, use various types of technologies to remember that your browser software visited our website.  The third-parties include entities that provide social media sharing opportunities, video players, and other diverse website functionality and services for our site.  These third parties may use browser cookies, web beacons, “Flash” cookies, and other technologies.  Some of these parties may collect Non-Personal Information that they use for online behavioral advertising, which is advertising based on which websites you visit.

Browser Cookies are small data files created by a website and stored on your computer.  Cookies enable us to recognize your browser on return visits to our Site and to remember your preferences.  You can disable or block cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent to your device   To learn more about browser cookies, visit allaboutcookies.org.

Web beacons are very small image files that are not visible to the human eye and which are used with and without browser cookies to enable the entity serving the beacon to remember that you visited a particular webpage.

Flash Player technology is software, separate from your browser, that enables the delivery and viewing of rich content and videos.  “Flash cookies” (or “Local Shared Objects”) are associated with the Flash Player software on your device and are often used to maintain settings and functionality.  Flash cookies can be deleted by visiting Adobe and following Adobe’s instructions regarding Flash cookies.  [http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html).

As a nonprofit organization, we do not display advertising on our site, however, as noted, certain third-party entities that we use to provide website functionality or social sharing may collect Non-Personal Information for the purposes of online behavior advertising.

Our website does not respond to “do not track” signals transmitted by web browsers, but we encourage you to visit the following links if you would like to opt out of  online behavioral advertising:  http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices or [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**Third Party Links and Tools:**

We include links to social networking sites and other sharing tools on the adult-directed pages of our sites.  Please be aware that those sites and tools have their own privacy policies and practices.  We encourage you to visit those sites to read those policies.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these third parties.

**A Note About Children’s Information:**

The ikeepsafe.org website contains special sections with activities intended for use by children under the age of 13.  We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children, and we do not include links to any third party websites or social sharing tools in areas of the site intended for children.  If we should learn that we have inadvertently collected personally identifiable information from children, we will promptly delete it.  If you have additional questions regarding our policies and practices related to children’s information, please contact us at [info@ikeepsafe.org](mailto:info@ikeepsafe.org).

**A Special Note About California Residents:**

We do not disclose any personal information to third parties for marketing purposes. For additional information about our privacy practices, or to review and request to have deleted any personal information you have shared with us, please send a request to info@ikeepsafe.org.

**How to Contact Us**

ikeepsafe.orgSM, iKeepSafePrivacy.com and iKeepSafePrivacy.org are owned by the Internet Keep Safe CoalitionSM group. Visitors to our websites may contact us by emailing [info@ikeepsafe.org](mailto:info@ikeepsafe.org).

To learn more about how we can help, leave us a message:

* * *

Subscribe to our monthly  
Privacy & Security newsletter.

iKeepSafe privacy professionals conduct an assessment of products that are used or intended for use in educational settings, bringing these products into compliance with federal and state privacy and children’s safety laws.

* Contact
* (202) 505-4408
* [iKeepSafe Coalition  
    C/O Leavitt Partners  
    601 New Jersey Avenue NW  
    Suite 350  
    Washington, DC 20001](https://www.google.com/maps/place/601+New+Jersey+Ave+NW+%23450,+Washington,+DC+20001/@38.8978502,-77.0137411,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x89b7b789f242842d:0x5e460c4cc3671b78!8m2!3d38.8978502!4d-77.0115524)

* Connect

© 2024 iKeepSafe. All rights reserved.
